axigen.com 2018-11-10

# AXIGEN Mail Server - Privacy Policy

Software Product: Axigen Mail Server  
Copyright since 2001 © Axigen Messaging SRL. All rights reserved.  
Axigen is a trademark of Axigen Messaging SRL (Axigen Messaging) 

Thank you for using Axigen Mail Server. Your privacy is very important to us. This Privacy Policy indicates how we collect and use personal data about you, in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), Romanian Data Protection Act, and any other national implementing laws, regulations, and secondary legislation, as amended or updated from time to time, when using the Software Product or accessing our Website. 

Such information may be used only and strictly to the purposes indicated herein. We shall not provide, sell, make available this information, except when this is expressly requested by law. 

Axigen Messaging has created this Privacy Policy in order to demonstrate our company's commitment to privacy. This page describes our policy regarding information gathering and dissemination practices. 

It’s important that you read this carefully and understand this Privacy Policy. By using our Website and our Software Product, you agree to these terms and conditions. If you don’t agree to the following terms and conditions, you should not use our Website, the Software Product, or Services.

We may, if needed, change any part of these terms of use without notice.. It is advisable that you check the Privacy Policy regularly.

About us

Axigen Messaging SRL (hereinafter referred to as “Axigen”) is the provider of Axigen Mail Server. We are registered in Romania at 61C Nicolae Caramfil Str., building B, first floor Entrance from Școala Herăstrău 014142, Bucharest. 

Registration: J40/11471/2012 

VAT ID: RO30754979 

Our responsibilities

If you are a registered Axigen customer or a visitor to our Website, we act as the ‘data controller’ of personal data. This means we determine how and why your data are processed. 

Your responsibilities

  1. Read this Privacy Policy
  2. If you are our customer, please also check the contracts between us: they may contain further details on how we collect and process your data.
  3. If you provide us with personal information about other people or if others give us your information, we will only use that information for the specific reason for which it was provided to us. By submitting the information, you confirm that you have the right to authorize us to process it on your behalf in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

## 1\. Information we collect. How we use such information.

### 1.1. Software Product use

When you are using the Software Product on your computer, server or servers, it periodically sends to us general information, such as the list and the number of domains, number of mailboxes, mailing lists used, the usage of add-ons and internal features, the languages used by the users (in aggregated form – in total and and per-domain), etc. 

No end-user identifiable information is sent as part of these statistics collection process. 

We collect such information solely for statistical purposes as to be able to develop the Software Product and design related customized offers by reference to your needs. 

If you wish to inspect the content of the statistics, you can enable a carbon copy to an email address of your choosing from within the configuration of our Software Product. 

### 1.2. Logs

We may also collect your IP address when you log in on our Website. 

We collect this information to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Website. Your IP address is used to gather broad demographic information. We use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests and for other purposes. Cookies help us to track visitors and their usage and preferences on our Website. 

If you do not agree with us using cookies, you can set your browser accordingly before accessing the Website. However, be advised that without the aid of cookies some features of the Website may not function properly. 

For more detailed information on how we use cookies, please see our Cookie Policy: https://www.axigen.com/legal/cookie-policy/. 

### 1.3. What about really sensitive data?

We don’t collect any "sensitive data" about you (like racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious / philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, genetic data, biometric data, health data, data about your sexual life or orientation, and offences or alleged offences) except when we have your specific consent, or when we have to to comply with the law. 

### 1.4. What about children’s data?

Axigen is a business-to-business service directed to and intended for use only by those who are 18 years of age or over. We do not target Axigen at children, and we do not knowingly collect any personal data from any person under 16 years of age. 

## 2\. Information you share. How we use such information.

### 2.1. Registration form

Our Website includes a download registration form, used by customers to request product downloads: https://www.axigen.com/mail-server/download/#license=trial. Our online registration form asks visitors for contact information (like their email address). 

We use contact data from our forms to occasionally send product updates, offers, and email surveys. This contact information is also used to contact the visitor when necessary (e.g. with respect to the change of this privacy policy, customer support, system alerts, etc.). Users may opt out of receiving future mailings; see the Choice / Opt-out section below. 

### 2.2. Email links

In various places on our Website, you will find links for sending us an email message.

We use your email address to send you a reply and we store your message only for later referral, in case you decide to contact us again. Your message and email address remain confidential unless you instruct otherwise. 

### 2.3. Feedback contact form

If you decide to contact us through our feedback form: https://www.axigen.com/about-us/feedback-form/, we will use your email address to send you a reply. We will store your email address and message only for later referral, in case you decide to contact us again. 

### 2.4. Newsletter subscription

By subscribing to our email newsletter, you provide us with your email address and you agree to occasionally receive a newsletter containing updates about our company and products until you unsubscribe. You may unsubscribe at any time, either from a specific list, by clicking the "Unsubscribe from this list" link at the bottom of any email received from us, or globally – from all lists – by requesting this via an email to [webmaster@axigen.com](mailto:webmaster@axigen.com). Subscription to our newsletter is optional and requires your consent. 

If you sign up for a specific email newsletter on the Axigen Messaging Website, you will only receive the email newsletter you have requested. You may occasionally receive an offer to sign up for a different newsletter, but you will not receive additional newsletters unless your specifically request them. 

## 3\. How and why we use your data

The data protection law means that we can only use your data for certain reasons and where we have a legal basis to do so. Here are the reasons for which we process your data: 

Improving Axigen products and services 

Testing features, product development roadmap. 

Legal basis for this data usage: contract, legitimate interests. 

Keeping Axigen products and services running 

Managing your requests, login and authentication, remembering your settings, processing payments. 

Legal basis: contract, legitimate interests. 

Customer support 

Notifying you of any changes to our service, solving issues via live chat support, phone, or email including any bug fixing. 

Legal basis for this data usage: contract. 

Marketing purposes 

Sending you emails and messages about new features, products and services, and content. 

Legal basis for this data usage: consent and legitimate interests. You may easily opt-out from receiving such messages at any time. 

Here is what each of these "legal bases" mean: 

Consent 

You have given clear consent for you to process your personal data for a specific purpose. 

You can change your mind! 

If you have previously given consent to our processing your data you can freely withdraw such consent at any time. You can do this by emailing us at [data-protection@axigen.com](mailto:data-protection@axigen.com). 

If you do withdraw your consent, and if we do not have another legal basis for processing your information, then we will stop processing your personal data. If we do have another legal basis for processing your information, then we may continue to do so subject to your legal rights. 

Contract 

Processing your data is necessary for a contract you have with us, or because we have asked you to take specific steps before entering into that contract. 

Legitimate interests 

Processing your data is necessary for our legitimate interests or the legitimate interests of a third party, provided those interests are not outweighed by your rights and interests. These legitimate interests are: 

  * gaining insights from your behaviour on our Website or in our app
  * delivering, developing, and improving the Axigen service
  * enabling us to enhance, customize, or modify our services and comms
  * determining whether marketing campaigns are effective
  * enhancing data security

In each case, these legitimate interests are only valid if they are not outweighed by your rights and interests. 

## 4\. External links

Our Website contains links to other websites, outside the control of Axigen Messaging, that we think you may find useful. If you click on these links, you will leave the Axigen Website and enter websites that may have privacy policies different than Axigen’s. Axigen Messaging is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. 

## 5\. Sharing of information and unsolicited communications

Aside from the third party involved in the processing of your payment, or an Axigen authorized partner in your local area, we do not share your personally identifiable information with any other entities. In addition, we will not send you any communications that you do not explicitly request from us (i.e. the only way for you to receive our email newsletter is if you choose to subscribe through a form on the Axigen Website). 

## 6\. Choice / Opt-out

Our Website provides users the following options for removing their information from our lists in order to not receive future communication from us: 

  1. To unsubscribe from a specific list, follow the "Unsubscribe from this list" link at the bottom of any email communication received from us;
  2. To unsubscribe from all lists, send us an email with this request to [webmaster@axigen.com](mailto:webmaster@axigen.com).

## 7\. Your rights

You can exercise your rights by sending us an email at [data-protection@axigen.com](mailto:data-protection@axigen.com). 

You have the right to access the information we hold about you. 

This includes the right to ask us supplementary information about: 

  * the categories of data we’re processing
  * the purposes of data processing
  * the categories of third parties to whom the data may be disclosed
  * how long the data will be stored (or the criteria used to determine that period)
  * your other rights regarding our use of your data

We will provide you with the information within one month of your request, unless doing so would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of other (e.g. another person’s confidentiality or intellectual property rights). We’ll tell you if we can’t meet your request for that reason. 

You have the right to make us correct any inaccurate personal data about you. 

You can object to us using your data for profiling you or making automated decisions about you. 

We will provide you a copy of your data in CSV or JSON format, so that you can provide it to another service. If you ask us and it is technically possible, we will directly transfer the data to the other service for you. We will not do so to the extent that this involves disclosing data about any other individual. 

You have the right to be ‘forgotten’ by us. 

You can do this by asking us to erase any personal data we hold about you, if it is no longer necessary for us to hold the data for purposes of your use of Axigen products and services. 

You have the right to lodge a complaint regarding our use of your data. 

Please tell us first, so we have a chance to address your concerns. If we fail in this, you can address any complaint to the Romanian Data Protection Supervisory Authority, either by calling their helpline or as directed on their website at [www.dataprotection.ro](http://www.dataprotection.ro/). 

Address: 

28-30 G-ral. Gheorghe Magheru Blvd.   
District 1, Postal code 010336   
Bucharest, Romania 

Phone: +40.318.059.211 / +40.318.059.212 

Fax: +40.318.059.602 

Email: anspdcp@dataprotection.ro 

Website: [www.dataprotection.ro](http://www.dataprotection.ro/)

How secure is the data we collect? 

We have physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect. For more information on our efforts to ensure your data is held in a secure manner, please see our data security policy. 

And please remember: 

You provide personal data at your own risk: unfortunately, no data transmission is guaranteed to be 100% secure. 

You are responsible of your username and password: keep them secret and safe! 

If you believe your privacy has been breached, please contact us immediately at [data-protection@axigen.com](mailto:data-protection@axigen.com). 

Where we store the data 

The personal data we collect is processed at our offices in Bucharest. 

By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing, or processing by us. If we transfer or store your information outside the EEA in this way, we will take steps to ensure that your privacy rights continue to be protected as outlined in this Privacy Policy. 

How long we store your data 

We will archive and stop actively using any personal identifiable information about you within 3 years from the last time you used Axigen. We will delete your personal data from our archives no later than 10 years from the last time you used Axigen or as agreed with you in a separate contract. 

## 8\. Notification of changes to our Privacy Policy

If we are going to use your personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify you via email. You will have a choice as to whether you agree or not to us using your information in this different manner. 

In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that affect user information already stored in our database, we will email users of our Software Product, as well as users who have opted in to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices. 

## 9\. Means of contacting us

If you have any further questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this Website and your interactions with it, or the Software Product, you can contact us by using the contact page: https://www.axigen.com/about-us/contact/.
